A Guide to the William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002 FA446
Rockefeller Archive Center
William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002
1843-1987
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, William Avery
FA446
2.42 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate.
135 prints and postcards.
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Other Finding Aids
For other Rockefeller family photographic holdings, please see the following finding aids:
FA445 Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001
FA447 John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003
FA448 William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
FA449 John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005
FA450 Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
FA451 John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007
FA454 Nelson A. Rockefeller photographs, Series 1008
FA452 Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009
FA453 David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Includes individual and group portraits as well as photographs of family homes and properties.
- William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, 1002
  Arrangement
  The series contains multiple subseries:
  1002A Lucy Rockefeller Briggs family. 1002B Mary Ann Rockefeller Rudd family. 1002C Franklin Rockefeller family.
  For ease of access, the material is further arranged by:
  Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, etc.).
  - Prints
    - Eliza Davison Rockefeller, 6 prints (Box P 1)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1859-1920; 5 prints (Box P 1)
    - Group Portraits - Children, 1 print (Box P 157, Folder 1)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 2 prints (Box P 1)
    - Homes - Cleveland, 1 print (Box P 1)
    - Homes - Moravia, NY, 1843-1917; 7 prints (Box P 1)
    - Homes - Owego, NY, 1917-1921; 12 prints and postcards. (Box P 2)
    - Homes - Richford, NY, 1920-1987; 40 prints (Box P 2)
    - Homes - Strongville, OH, 1854-1855; 3 prints (Box P 3)
    - Mrs. Levingston, 1 print (Box P 3)
    - Relatives, 1883; 5 prints (Box P 3)
    - William Avery Rockefeller, 5 prints (Box P 3)
  - Oversized
    - William Avery Rockefeller family, 2 prints (Box O 1)
    - Group Portraits, 2 prints (Box O 1)
    - Group Portraits, 1897; 1 print (Box O 2)
    - Homes, 1864; 10 prints (Box O 2)
    - Relatives - Homes, 2 prints (Box O 1)
    - William Avery Rockefeller family, 6 prints (Box O 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Portraits of Lucy Avery Rockefeller and Eliza Davison Rockefeller
  - Lucy Rockefeller Briggs famly, 1002A
    - Prints
      - Lucy Rockefeller Briggs family, 1868-1910; 7 prints (Box P 3)
  - Mary Ann Rockefeller Rudd family, 1002B
    - Prints
      - Mary Ann Rockefeller Rudd family, 1930; 6 prints (Box P 3)
  - Franklin Rockefeller family, 1002C
    - Prints
      - Franklin Rockefeller family, 9 prints and postcards. (Box P 3)
    - Oversized
      - Franklin Rockefeller family, 3 prints (Box O 1)